Hello
大家好
Hi, My name is Pearl Hoddling
我叫Pearl Hoddling
And I'm a senior in Kirkland House
是来自Kirkland House的大四学生
And I'm here to ask you to join me this Saturday
我希望你们能在这周六上午10点
from 10 to 2 for free pancakes from Hendriana's table and Maquat
到下午2点参加Hendriana和Maquat的免费薄饼计划
Nine years ago
九年前
my dad was diagnosed with Parkinson's disease
我父亲被诊断出患有帕金森症
a neurological disorder
一种神经疾病
Though he, my family and I have gone through many ups and downs
尽管他 我的家人和我经历了很多起伏坎坷
both physical and emotional
既是生理上的 也是情感上的
I finally found a way to help
我最终找到一种方式来献绵薄之力
a definitive op
一个明确的选择
I want to put on this event ＂Pancakes for Parkinson's＂
我想参与这个活动"帕金森薄饼"
for a few years now
已经办了好几年了
And I didn't get the guts to do it until this year
直到今年我才鼓起勇气参加
Thank you. Tal
谢谢你 Tal
for helping me to get over my procrastination
帮我克服我的拖延症
and start building a positive spiral
开始积极地
for finding a cure for Parkinson's disease
来寻找治疗帕金森的方法
All donations will go directly to Michael J.Fox foundation
所有捐赠直接捐给Michael J.Fox
for Parkinson's research
帕金森研究基金
So please come between 10 and 2 this Saturday
期待周六10点到2点你们的参与
to enjoy pancake for a good cause
出于善意来享用薄饼
Thank you
谢谢
Hi, My name is Maureen Hilton
我叫Maureen Hilton
And I'm a fellow student of this class
我也是这门课的一个学生
And I work here at Harvard College
我在哈佛工作
I would like to invite you all
我想邀请诸位
to my positive psychology presentation
来参加我的积极心理学报告
which is next Friday
是下周五
May 9th at 2 pm in Harvard Hall
5月9号下午两点在哈佛礼堂
The main goal hope for next Friday
下周五的主要目的
is bring together in one room
是希望能聚集
people interested in positive psychology here at Harvard
哈佛所有对积极心理学有兴趣的人们
This includes Harvard administrators of all levels
包括各层次的哈佛管理人员
the class's teaching staff, students
这门课的教师 学生
whether they are alumni of past positive psychology class
不管是曾经上过幸福课的
or current students of this class
或是正在上的
whether college or extension school
不管是本科还是继续教育
or students who hope that there's positive psychology here in the future
或者希望未来能拥有积极心态的学生
and certainly anyone you would like to invite
以及你们想邀请的任何人
Please let this be an opportunity for you to share your stories
希望这能成为你们一次分享故事
and the reasons why this class has impacted your life
以及这门课如何影响你人生的机会
And in addition
此外
to help the networking and socializing part of this gathering
为了协助这次聚会的联系和交流
the Harvard Callbacks will be singing
哈佛Callback合唱团会进行演出
the seniors who you may know - Gina
你们可能认识的大四学生 Gina
Skylar and Kedar will be singing their solos
Skylar和Kedar会表演他们
for possibly the last time here at Harvard
可能在哈佛的最后一次独唱
And there will be free food
现场会提供免费食物
Again, please feel free to bring and invite anyone you like
诸位可以随意邀请想邀请的人
especially fellow students who are hoping
尤其是希望未来还能开设
there's another positive psychology course in the future
幸福课这样一门课程的同学
No RSVP's necessary
无需回复
Just come
来就行了
Because what we'll definitely leave a lasting impression
因为我们给哈佛教务处留下的
on the Harvard administration
最深印象
is if together we create a little peak experience
就是我们一起享受愉悦的感觉
and fill a room of people who come together
并聚集了一屋子为了幸福课
for the promotion of positive psychology
能有所提升的人
Please come next Friday
希望你们下周五能来
May 9th
5月9号
at 2 pm at Harvard Hall
下午两点在哈佛礼堂
Thank you
谢谢
I don't really know what to say
我也不知该说什么
So I ask someone to say it for me
所以我找了别人来替我说
[VIDEO: THE MUPPET SHOW ＂Saying Goodbye＂]
(录像:大青蛙布偶秀"道别")
Saying goodbye
挥手道别
going away
扬帆启程
Seems like goodbye's such a hard thing to say
"再见"一词哽塞在喉
Touching our hands
双手紧握
wondering why
想问为何
It's time for saying goodbye
又是别离时分
Kermit!
Kermit
Goodbye!
再见
Goodbyyyyyyyye!
Saying goodbye
挥手道别
why is it sad?
满心伤悲
Makes us remember the good times we've had
又回忆起过去的好时光
Much more to say
千言万语
foolish to try
欲言又止
It's time for saying goodbye
又是别离时分
Don't want to leave
不舍离开
but we both know
你我都懂
Sometimes it's better to go
有时离开也许更好
Somehow I know
而我知道
we'll meet again
终会重逢
Not sure quite where and I don't know just when
虽不知何时何地
You're in my heart
你永在我心
so until then
重逢之前
It's time for saying goodbye
又是别离时分
Somehow I know
而我知道
we'll meet again
终会重逢
Not sure quite where and I don't know just when
虽不知何时何地
You're in my heart so until then
你永在我心 重逢之前
Wanna smile
带着微笑
Wanna cry
也噙着泪
Saying goodbye~~~La la la la
与你道别 啦啦啦啦
la la la la
啦啦啦啦
It's time for saying goodbye
又是别离时分
La la la la
啦啦啦啦
la la la la
La la la la-la la la
啦啦啦啦
So I need your help
我需要你们的帮助
I'm so very nervous
我十分紧张
What can I do?
我该怎么办
Meditate? Thank you
冥想? 谢谢
Exercise? Now?
锻炼 现在?
You mean dance? OK
你是说跳舞吗
Tell a joke
讲个笑话
You tell a joke
你们给我讲吧
What else? Any suggestions?
还有什么别的建议没
Hug someone! Good idea
拥抱 好主意
At least 12 hugs, right? Yeah
至少要12个拥抱 对吧
Anything else? Deep breath! OK. Good
还有什么 深呼吸 很好
So it's OK to be nervous? Thank you
紧张也没关系? 谢谢
Feel better already
我已经感觉好多了
So this is for me the last class at Harvard
这是我在哈佛的最后一节课了
Who else is in the same boat?
还有谁也是一样
Wow. Your last class
你的最后一节课
What I'd like to do today is
我今天想做的是
summarize what we've gone through some of the journey
尽可能地总结一下我们一路来
as much as possible
所得的一些收获
And what I'd like to do is to share that
我想和你们分享
the responsibility of summarizing
这个总结的责任
to share it with you
你们也要一起分享
so I'd like to start with you thinking and reflecting about the course
所以我想从你们思考和回忆课程内容开始
In other words, we are going to run the class today
换言之我们今天这节课
like a small intimacy section
就像个亲密互动环节
Afterwards I'll go through what I think of some of the highlights
之后我会讲一遍我认为的
main points from the semester
这学期的一些重点知识
So I want to start with a time-in
我想先从你们开始
an opportunity for you to reflect
给你们机会回顾一下
And specifically I would like you to reflect
我尤其希望你们能够回顾
on the following things and actually write them down
以下主题 并把它们写下来
So go over your notes or go over your mental notes
翻阅一下你们的笔记 搜索一下脑海
and write down at least two things that were particularly meaningful
写下至少两样你觉得这学期最有意义
or interesting for you from this semester
或你觉得最有趣的东西
whether it's something that you heard in lecture
不管是课上听到的内容
something you discussed in section
小组讨论时的话题
something that you read
你阅读时读到的东西
something that you talked about with your friends after class
课后你和朋友讨论过的
and somehow was connected to your experience here
和这门课有所联系的问题
anything or at least two things that were personally meaningful
什么都可以 至少两样对你来说最有意义
and interesting to you
或最有趣的东西
So this is the first thing
这是第一个内容
The second thing that I'd like you to write down
我想让你们写下的第二个内容
and you may have done it before
你们可能以前试过
You may have written it before
可能以前写过
at least two commitments that you are making
至少两样你所决心做的转变
two behavioral changes or attitudinal changes
两种行为转变或态度转变
two commitments that you are taking upon yourself
两样你要付诸实施的改变
now that the semester is almost over
既然学期也都快结束了
So again, two meaningful or interesting ideas at least
再说一遍 至少两样有意义或有趣的事
and at least two commitments
以及至少两个转变
whether it's in the form of rituals
不管是建立习惯
attitudinal change or behavioral change
态度转变 或行为转变
So take just a few minutes to do that in a time-in
花一点时间把它们写下来
OK
好
Now what I'd like you to do - and this is completely voluntary
现在我希望你们做的 当然是完全
of course
自愿的
is share some of the things that you've learned
就是分享一些你们学过的
or at least one thing that you learned that was personally meaningful
或至少一样这学期学过的有意义
or interesting to you from this semester
或很有趣的东西
and if you feel comfortable
以及如果你们愿意的话
the one of the two commitments
那两样转变其中的一样
or both commitments that you've taken upon yourselves
或两样一起分享给
with the person next to you
你身边的那位同学
or with two people next to you
或你身边的两位同学
So take just 5 minutes to share with one another
花五分钟来彼此分享一下
one interesting or meaningful thing
一样有趣或有意义的事
and one commitment or two
以及一到两种转变
OK
好
I hope you continue the rest of your day
我希望你们在今天或人生中
for the rest of your life sharing what you've learned
余下的时间还能继续分享学过的知识
what you are learning
正在学的知识
how you are growing
你如何成长
Now what I would like to do is
我现在想做的是
hear some of you just talk about you know one thing
听听你们讲讲一样
perhaps that you find
你认为它
found interesting or meaningful
有趣或有意义的事
that could be directly from the class or something tangential
可以是课堂内容 也可以来自其他涉猎
but what was meaningful or interesting for you this semester
但却是这学期对你来说有趣或有意义的东西
And we have some microphones spread around the room
我们把话筒在整个教室传递
So if anyone would like to be the first one, to volunteer
有没有人愿意做第一个自愿讲讲的
remember courage is not about not having fear
还记得吗 勇气并不是没有畏惧
it's about having fear and going ahead anyway
而是有了畏惧还坚持向前
If courage was about not having fear
如果勇气是没有畏惧
I would not be teaching this class
我就不会来教这门课了
Elizabeth
I think for me what the most important thing was was the idea
我觉得对我来说最重要的东西就是
of self-concordant goal
自我和谐的目标
not being frivolous or selfish
不是浮躁或自私的
but actually being something that
而是一种每个人都应该
one should actively pursue and can help the people around you
积极追求的 可以帮助你身边的人
more than by pursuing that what you are told to pursue
而非别人让你追求什么 你就追求什么
Great. So essentially dissolving this divide between self and the other
很好 消除自我和他人之间的分歧
And remember
还记得吗
the Dalai Lama - how surprised he was when he came to the west
达赖喇嘛 当他到了西方国家后有多惊讶
and he heard our word for compassion
他听说我们的"同情"这个词
means essentially compassion toward others
指的是对其他人的同情
whereas Sawai in Tibetan means compassion toward others
而藏语中Sawai既指对他人的同情
and compassion toward oneself
也包括对自我的同情
They go hand in hand; they are intertwined
它们是彼此交融的
So identifying our self-concordant goals
所以要找到自我和谐的目标
is very much about helping ourselves
很大程度上就是要帮助自我
and ultimately making the world a better place
并最终使世界变得更美好
Wonderful. Thank you
非常好 谢谢你
I found the Roger Bannister story really meaningful to me
我觉得Roger Bannister对我来说很有意义
especially because now I know nothing is impossible
尤其因为我现在明白了一切皆有可能
even there are scientists telling you things are impossible
即使科学家说有些事是不可能的
You can still achieve them
你也还是可以做到的
Right. You know so often people tell us that it's impossible
对 人们经常会跟说 这是不可能的
you can't do it
你做不到
And we have that voice at the back of our mind
我们的脑海中总是回响着这样的声音
those limiting beliefs
这些狭隘的想法
whether it's limiting beliefs about how we can feel
这种狭隘既包括对我们的感觉
can feel; and what we can achieve
也包括我们所能做到的事
And what Roger Bannister's story does
而Roger Bannister的故事
what it helps us do is chip away some of these limitations
能够帮我们打破一些这样的束缚
and understand our potential
挖掘自身的潜能
Thank you. Yes
谢谢你 请说
The day when you told the story about your grandmother
那天你提到了关于你祖母的故事
and how she was able to still see so much beauty in the world
她是如何历经坎坷后 终于看到
after everything she had been through
世间种种美景的
was very, very moving for me
这深深地打动了我
And that was a very unique experience to
在这样的学术氛围中能如此感动
be so emotionally moved in this academic setting
实在是一种特殊而难得的体验
So that was really powerful
真的很有力量
And that really made me reevaluate the way
也使我重新审视自己
I look at my life and the way that
看待人生的方式以及
I appreciate the things that I have
珍惜我所有的东西的方式
Thank you, Thank you
谢谢 谢谢
I really like the idea that we can get over things
我很喜欢那个"我们忘记坏事情
bad things a lot quicker than we would anticipate
比我们想象的快得多"的观点
I just think that you know so often
我经常思考这一点
we cheat ourselves of so much success
我们总是骗自己说有多成功
so much potential, pleasure
多么有潜能 多么快乐
but I think, you know
但我想
just the idea of going forward and
朝着目标向前冲
that we will ultimately get over it if it doesn't work out
就算没能达到也会最终释怀的想法
That's really important
是非常重要的
Right, yes. So you know
没错
just like when we achieve something good
我们有所成就时
we go back to base level and feel like as we did before
能回复平和 感觉就像从前一样
also when we fail
而当我们失败时
And it's a real liberating feeling to know that
要是知道我们是能重新振作的
that we are resilient
是会很快恢复的
that we will recover
是很能让人解脱的
Thank you
谢谢
Yes
请说
For me, it was important to realize balance between the rat racer
在我看来 找到竞争主义者和享乐主义者之间的
and the hedonist
平衡点很重要
finding the balance between short term benefit and long term benefit
以及短期益处和长期益处之间的平衡
Right. You know
是的
so much of our lives is about ＂either or＂
人生经常会遇到"非此则彼"的情况
Either I'm a successful rat racer
要么我是个成功的竞争主义者
or I'm a hedonist who has given up essentially on success
要么就是个放弃成功的享乐主义者
Whereas what we can very  often do is reconcile the two
而我们其实通常都能将两者融合
You know, eat the cake and leave it whole - so it seems
就像咬一口蛋糕还保持其基本完整
Future benefit and present benefit in one
长远益处和近期益处的结合
Thank you
谢谢
To seek to be known and not validated - and the way you taught the class
被人所知而非被证明 以及你教课的方式
opening up, let's say
比如上课前会讲
each individual failure you had in your life
你人生中经历的许多失败
I found myself
我就觉得自己
my own failures - they are different
我自己的失败 它们是不同的
but they are the same
但又是统一的
I felt less lonely
我觉得没那么孤单了
Thank you. You know when
谢谢 你知道吗
what I shared at I think the very first class here was what Carl Rogers said
我在第一节课就讲过的 Carl Rogers说过
which is ＂what is most personal is most general＂
"最个人的也是最大众的"
Because deep down humanity is humanity, is humanity
因为从本质来说 这些都是人性
And when we live in the world with the desire to be known
当我们活在这世上 有被了解的欲望
expressing ourselves
表达自我
that's I think when we can reach out most to others
这是我们最能和他人触碰的时候
whether it's in a romantic relationship
不管是爱情
whether it's in friendships
友情
whether it's in a classroom
或是同学之间
Thank you
谢谢
Yes
请说
One thing I would take away from this class is
我从这门课上学到的一点就是
to be conscious about being grateful
要学会感恩
because sometimes I feel that
因为有时我感觉
you take for granted the people you love the most
人们总是把最爱的人当做理所当然
To be grateful - there are so many treasures of happiness
感恩 我们的周围和内心
of well being all around us and within us
都有那么多快乐和幸福
And the challenge is just to open our eyes
最重要的是睁开我们的双眼
to appreciate them
去感受它们
Yes
请说
What was really amazing to me
对我来说特别棒的就是
was how open others where not in the class
这门课对其他不是学生的人很开放
such as family and other friends not in the class
比如家人以及其他不学这门课的同学
to also take on this change in their life
同样也能这样改变他们的人生
They didn't see it as some cookie self-help thing
他们并不会刻意感觉到这对他们有好处
but really as
而是
＂Oh yeah, maybe I should take note of
"对 也许我该记下所有
all the things I'm grateful for in my life＂and other exercises
我生活中该感恩的东西" 以及其他的
Yeah, you know
是的
this is paying it forward
这就是传递
Sometimes we are so afraid to talk about things that matter to us
有时我们很害怕说出自己看重的东西
And when we do
而当我们说出它时
and when we are real
当我们是真实的
when we are genuine
当我们是真挚的
when we express ourselves
当我们表达自我时
these things are contagious
这些东西是会传染的
And we pay it forward
我们会将其传递出去
And then they pay it forward
它们再继续不断传递
Thank you. Yes
谢谢 请说
Before taking this class
在学这门课之前
I blame my mood and my happiness a lot on those going around me
我将自己的悲喜都归咎于周围的事物
like my circumstances
比如我的环境
So taking this class really helped me
学这门课真的帮到我很多
aware the circumstances really don't control your happiness level
意识到周围环境其实并不会掌控你的快乐
that I have more than an active role like how I feel
我应该更积极地了解自己的感受
Right. You know
是的
remember one of the things we talked about is that
还记得我们讲过
at least I don't believe that things necessarily happen for the best
至少我不认为什么事都能一帆风顺
You know there are some times where there are bad circumstances
有时我们会遇到坏情况
poor circumstances
糟糕的情况
hard circumstances
艰难的情况
the challenge though is how can we make the best
最大的挑战其实是我们如何
of that which have happened
能更好地利用发生的一切
And we do have much more control over it than we think
我们确实比自己想象的更有力量来掌控
Yes
请说
The class allowed me so many times during almost every day
这门课让我几乎每天都能很多次地
to understand something is part of me being human
感受到我是个普通人
as part my permission to be human
我允许自己为人
rather than conceive it as my feelings
而不是自己臆想出来的
or something that I wasn't doing well enough
或者总想着我没做好的事
So the permission - you know
允许为人
I've repeated it for so many times and I'll continue to repeat it
我反复多次提到了它 并将继续提到
until use every last minute that I have to do it
即使到了生命最后几分钟也会继续
because it's really on so many levels the foundation of well being
因为从很多方面来说它确实是幸福的基础
And unfortunately too much in our culture today
不幸的是我们如今的文化
what is going on is what I call
过于强调我所说的
＂the great deception＂
"巨大的骗局"
where we think well everyone is doing great except for me
我们认为每个人都很棒 就我不行
So I'm going to pretend that I'm doing great too
所以我要假装我也很棒
And then we become part of that great deception
然后我们就成了"巨大骗局"的一部分
reinforcing it
一定要反复强调
The permission to be human
允许为人
Yes
请讲
The whole piece about perfectionism
关于完美主义的那些内容
I have never seen myself as a perfectionist
我从没觉得自己是个完美主义者
and I think it's just kind of self denial
我觉得那是种自我否定
So through the exercises in the course as well as
通过课堂上的练习以及
you know in the book
课本的内容
different readings that we've done have really allowed me to
我们做的各种阅读 真的使我
explore that, and accept that
去探索 去接受它
and make proactive changes in my life to grow away from that
并主动地作出改变来远离它
Great. You know perfectionism is again another thing that so many people hide
很好 完美主义同样是人们经常隐藏的
because perfectionist almost by definition doesn't want to show the weakness
因为完美主义者从定义上说就不愿意显露出弱点
And as I mentioned in the class
正如我在课上所说的
unperfectionism for me has been the most important
我认为不完美主义是在向着
in terms of my progression toward becoming happier
幸福前进的道路上最重要的一点
Accepting failure as an inevitable
接受不可避免的失败
accepting that life is not a straight line
接受人生不会是一条直线
but rather a spiral with ups and downs
而是有起有伏的螺旋
along with the general trajectory
但主轴仍然在
as improvement, growth and permission
也就是进步 成长 和允许为人
So for me one of the things that really resonated
我觉得最有共鸣的一点就是
was the idea of reframing the question
就是重新构建问题
At the very beginning
在学期刚开始时
you spoke about the fact that there was the 21 to 1 ratio
你讲到消极和积极的研究
of negative to positive research
所得到的21:1的比例
And as someone who will be going into research in neurobiology
对于我这样马上要进行神经生物学研究的人来说
it was really interesting just reframing of a world view
能够重建世界观是很有趣的
just start thinking of
开始思考
well perhaps
也许
start looking at what is working in terms of research
开始思考对于研究来说什么是最重要的
And, so I will take that with me into my academics
我会在自己的学术领域中用到它
The importance of questions - questions create our reality
问题的重要性 问题能创造我们的现实
Remember the question of the children on the bus
还记得公车上的孩子们的问题吗
which most people completely missed
很多人都忽视了
remember years and years of research that was done in the inner cities
年复一年我们在城市中对高危人群
with at risk population
进行研究
where they missed the answer to how can we improve their lives
却总是找不到改善他们生活的方法
They missed it because they did not also ask the positive question
因为他们没有问出积极的问题
And it applies into every area of our lives as I'll talk about soon
我很快会讲 这也适用于我们生活的各个方面
Yes
请说
Before, I always procrastinate
此前我一直是个拖延的人
That is my big problem for my academic
这是我学习中的大问题
Now I improved a lot
现在我进步了很多
Thank you very much
非常感谢你
Procrastination - you know
拖延症
70 percent of students in universities complain about procrastination
70%的大学生抱怨说有拖延症
It's a huge issue
这是个大问题
And one of the ways to overcome it
克服它的一种方式
the best way to overcome it is to just do it
克服它的最好方式就是去做
Just start - remember the five minute take-off
还记得五分钟休息吗
That's so important
那非常重要
Thank you
谢谢
Yes
请说
I was just really
我对我们
really impressed with the reading that we read by Gilbert
阅读的Gilbert的作品印象非常深刻
that was talking about how the good luck in your life
讲的是关于生活中的好运
and the wonderful circumstances you find yourself in
以及你觉得自己置身的美好状态
are really your own making
其实都是你自己创造的
And by changing your outlook and your patterns
通过改变你的外表和衣着
you can really make a difference in your happiness day to day
你可以每日逐渐改变自己的幸福感
Yeah. You know so many people live lives and think
很多人活着会想
＂well…＂
"这个..."
only I didn't meet that person
要是我没遇到这个人就好了
if only this hasn't happen to me
要是这种事情没发生在我身上
I would have been happy
我就会很幸福的
And understanding that so much of it is
要明白这其中很大一部分
determined by our perception is very empowering
都是由我们的理解决定的是很重要的
Yes
请说
What has been most meaningful for me
对我来说最有意义的
has been in fact that this class exists
其实就是这门课的存在
and that there are so many people interested in happiness
有这么多人关心幸福
cause you know the culture here at Harvard
因为在哈佛这样的氛围中
we don't always get the chance to really think about it
我们不一定总有机会来思考这个
And as you said, you know it's
正如你所说
you are just reminding us what we already know
你只是提醒我们一些已经知道的事
but it's also letting us know that we are not crazy for knowing it
也让我们知道 我们了解它是正常的
Yeah, we are not
是的
We are not alone
我们并不孤单
And we need that reminder and other people need that reminder
我们需要有人提醒 其他人也需要
And by reminding other people
通过提醒其他人
we also remind ourselves
我们也提醒了自己
Thank you
谢谢
Yes
请说
For me it's the concept of integrity
我觉得是正直的概念
because I think we are all honest people
因为我认为我们都是诚实的人
but it's the little things at times each day
但就是每天的各种小事情
when we compromise our beliefs
让我们的信仰屈服
or act in a way that doesn't align with how we think we should
或者让我们言行不一
and that that really takes toll on our self esteem
这会对我们的自尊造成影响
And so the idea of being constantly aware of and maintaining our integrity
所以时刻意识到并保持我们的正直
I think really stands to helps us feel better about ourselves
能让我们对自我感觉更良好
Because when we tell the truth
当我们说真话时
we are communicating a certain message to ourselves
其实正给自己传递了某种信息
when we express ourselves
当我们表达自我时
we are communicating a certain message to ourselves
我们在给自己传递某种信息
And the message is my words count; I count
这个信息就是我的话有分量 我有分量
When we express
当我们表达
＂we are good enough＂
"我很棒"
don't need to put on a facade or impress
无需过分想给他人留下印象
Then the message
而这个信息
the self perception theory actually enhances
这个自我知觉理论能提升
how we feel about ourselves
我们对自身的看法
not to mention that it helps interpersonal communication
更不用说对人际关系的提升了
And the world would be a better place
也能使世界变得更美好
if more and more people acted with integrity
如果越来越多人能够正直
And again, self and others divide dissolves
那么同样自我和他人之间的分歧就会消除
Yes
请说
One the the phrases that you shared with us
你在课堂上和我们分享的
in your lectures that's really impacted me
一句话深深震撼了我
and I've actually embraced it as a kind of personal mantra is
我事实上已经将其作为了座右铭
＂learn to fail or fail to learn; there's no other way＂
"学会失败 或从失败中学习 没有别的法子"
And I kind of realized throughout the course, this class
经过这门课的学习 我意识到
what a perfectionist I have been
我曾经是个怎样的完美主义者
and how much time throughout my life
以及我人生中有多少次
my earliest memories have stuck really torturing myself
我的早期回忆一直在折磨自己
the anxiety and fear of making a mistake
焦虑 以及对犯错的恐惧
and to reframe that and really look at those inevitable moments
重构这些 真正回头看那些不可避免的
where I messed up as you know fuel for moving forward, as opportunities
失败时刻 能成为我前进的动力
has been wildly liberating
我面前突然一片开阔
So I thank you for that
非常感谢你
Thank you
谢谢
The notion of ＂learn to fail and fail to learn＂
"学会失败 从失败中学习"的概念
as you know is my personal mantra as well
其实也是我的个人座右铭
It's very liberating
它能让人解脱
It's liberating within the context of relationship
在人际关系中
within the context of our academic performance
在学业成绩中
within the context of an organization on every level
在一个组织的各个层面中
And it's important to understand that there is no other way to learn
重要的是要知道没有其他更好的学习方法
whether it's to draw a circle or to walk
不管是画圆圈或学走路
It's just part of life
这只是人生的一部分
And if we accept it
如果我们接受它
we are much happier for it
我们就能更快乐
Thank you
谢谢
Elizabeth
What's really been really meaningful to me in deciding
对我来说特别有意义的就是
what concentration to pursue
真正要专心追求的东西
is the idea of happiness is ultimate currency
快乐是最终的目的
and trying to kind of eliminate outside influences
要试图消除外界的影响
and really think about what is meaningful to me
认真思考对我来说有意义的到底是什么
and what will make me happy in what I study
在我所学的东西中什么能让我快乐
So thank you
谢谢
The ultimate currency
最终目的
you know many people say about Americans
很多人说美国人
that one of the reasons why the levels of depression are on the rise
之所以抑郁水平不断攀升
one of the reasons why there are so many unhappy people
之所以有那么多不快乐的人
is because Americans have too high expectations
其中一个原因就是美国人有过高的期望
And that's not true
这是错的
I disagree with it; and the research disagrees with it
我不同意 研究也不能证明这一点
It's not about having high versus low expectations
这不是高期望或低期望的问题
it's about having right versus wrong expectations
而是正确或错误的期望的问题
And it applies to, to many areas
这适用于很多领域
but one of the things to understand is that
但我们要明白的一点是
where do we look to gain gratification from our life
我们在人生中从何处获得满足
Is it from, again getting the next accolade
是来自下一句赞美
the next promotion or the people tell us how wonderful our concentration is?
下一次升职 或人们说我们有多棒吗
Or is it from doing what we want to do
还是来自我们想做的事
in other words, being determined by the ultimate currency
换言之我们最终的目的所决定的事
and understanding that happiness is the ultimate currency?
而最终的目的就是快乐
Thank you
谢谢
Yes
请说
I feel that all this semester and all this year in fact
我觉得这整个学期 这一整年
I have been trying to
我都一直在
I have been either going to class or running to lab or
要么上课 要么跑向实验室
just finding some way to fill up every hour of my day
寻找方法来填满我的每一天
And it seems like I'm constantly running from one place to another
似乎我永远在从一处跑向另一处
And it seems all my life I have been
似乎我整个人生
just essentially trying to fill up every hour of my day
都在试图填满每一分钟
And I feel what's really important and
我觉得特别重要的
what I really got from this is what you said about
我真的学到的就是你所说的
doing less is more
做得少其实是更多
And that's something I'm definitely going to take
我会很认真地在我接下来
like keep in mind the next three years when I'm here
在哈佛的三年中将这一点铭记于心
Yeah, less is more
对 做得少其实是更多
Quantity affects quality
数量会影响质量
And we so often wonder you know
我们经常好奇
＂how come I am unhappy?＂
"我为什么不快乐"
I have so many things in my life that are wonderful and amazing
我人生中有这么多美好的东西
And that could be part of the problem
这可能就是问题的一部分
Because more is not always better
因为更多不一定意味着更好
Not easy to simplify - that's so very important
要把事情简化很难 这是很重要的
So very important
非常重要
Yes
请说
The concept of simplicity on the other side of complexity
复杂性另一面的简单性的概念
is so awful for me, because you know
我觉得非常奇妙
when you grow up in life
当一个人成长时
you add all these variables and it becomes more and more complicated
就会加入各种各样的变量 变得越来越复杂
And as a is certain frustration about not being able to simplify
不能把问题简化是很让人沮丧的
But when you say at the top of the complexity
但你说到了复杂的顶点后
is when you realize the beauty
你会发现那种美
realizing that the simplicity comes after complexity
发现简单是出现在复杂之后
not before complexity
而非复杂之前
And the knowledge of complexity
而对复杂性的理解
that's an amazing concept
那是个非常棒的概念
So Oliver Wendell Holmes talks about the simplicity
Oliver Wendell Holmes讲到了
on the other side of complexity
复杂性另一面的简单性
And that applies whether it's to ideas - and again this class
这适用于不管是... 这门课大部分内容
most of it is very simple
都是很简单的
And there were no very complicated concepts here
没有什么特别复杂的概念
But many of them are the simplicity on the other side of complexity
但它们很多都是复杂性另一面的简单
Same on the individual level
对个人来说也是一样
Very often we go through hardships and our life is so difficult
我们经常会遇到困难 生活很艰难
We go through a crisis, through a crucible
我们会经历危机 严酷的考验
And what we need to do to understand
而我们要做的就是明白
when we are going through that complexity and hardship
当我们经历了这些复杂 艰难
and the crucible and the difficulties
严峻的考验和坎坷起伏之后
is that there is simplicity on the other side
另一面就是简单
Very often all we need to do is hang on
通常我们要做的往往就是坚持
Just wait a little bit longer
再等待一会儿
And there'll be more clarity
就会更清楚明了
more growth
更能成长
more development
更能进步
more joy at the end of it
最终更快乐
Yes
请说
On your passing on the mic
在传递话筒时
I was like
我在想
＂Oh my God, I don't really have anything to say
"天啊 我不知该说什么
There are so many people, I will never do that.＂
太多人了 我没法做到的"
And then you said courage is not about fearless
然后你说勇气不是没有畏惧
but about having fear and doing it anyway
而是有了畏惧还坚持向前
So I just threw my pack over the wall
所以我一下就把顾虑都抛弃了
I was like＂Give me that mic! I'm gonna do it!＂
就像"给我话筒 我要说!"
And it's in my hand and I'm speaking
而它现在在我手上 我在说话
So thank you for that
所以非常感谢
That's what it is about
就是这样
It's about behavioral change
这就是行为转变
Not in theory. Good
而不是理论 很好
Yes
请说
You've spoken in the past few lectures about in an anonymous world
你前几节课讲了关于匿名的世界
and about how we would live if our action is anonymous
如果一切行为是匿名的 我们会如何生活
And I think that knowing what we want and actually pursuing
我认为知道我们真正想要的并勇敢追求
what we want is or can be really challenging
我们想要的东西是很有挑战性的
even frightening
甚至是让人畏惧的
It just seems like you really know what you want and pursued
能够真正了解自己想要的
and pursue what you want
并一心追求它
And I think that is something to be really proud of
我觉得这是非常值得自豪的
And you definitely seem to practice what you preach and teach
而你确实实践了你所教给我们的东西
And I have enormous amount of respect for you because of that
因此我对你有着崇高的敬意
Thank you
谢谢
There are many things
你讲过很多东西
but one thing I'm really learned from this class is
但有一样我确实学到的就是
it is important to focus on what we really, really like to do
专注于我们真正想做的事
You said many time in the class
你在课堂上说过很多次
teaching is your calling
教书就是你的使命
And I can see how much you enjoy teaching
我能看得出来你有多热爱教学
And it was really inspiring to me
这让我很有感触
So I think I will remember that
我会记住这一点
and I will keep looking for my calling
并不断寻找我的使命
and what I really, really like to do
我真正想做的到底是什么
Thank you
谢谢
Yes
请说
Let's take someone with the microphone
找到拿着话筒的人
And we'll get it to you
把话筒给你
Anyone has a microphone?
有人有话筒吗
Wait. OK
好的
I used to be the kind of person who like run away from my problems
我以前是个总喜欢逃避问题的人
and I used to try to ignore them
总是试图忽视问题
until they went away
直到它们消失
And I don't do that anymore
而现在我不再这样了
Cause I know that if I'm unhappy
因为我知道如果我不开心
the only person who can do something about it is me
唯一能够解决的人就是我自己
And I need to make a change
我要做出改变
And this class has given me all sorts of tools to do that
这门课给我了很多这样做的帮助
So thank you
谢谢
Thank you
I just wanted to thank you for the idea of the power of commitment
我想谢谢你告诉我们承诺的力量
because it helped me get my job
它帮助我找到了工作
you know and something that I want to do
一边是我想做的事
which is journalism versus something that I wasn't excited about
也就是记者 一边是我不太感兴趣的
doing which is like PR
公共关系
So I wanted to thank you for that
我想为此感谢你
because you know I decided to jump into it
因为你使我决定投身其中
and throw my pack over the wall
抛弃一切顾虑
And that's why I got it. So thank you
所以我才找到自己想要的工作 谢谢
You know
事实上
Hi. Neiman fellows
粉丝们好
Yes
是的
I remember that you talked about when you stretch a muscle
我记得你说过当拉伸肌肉时
it gets stronger
它会变强
and brought up the idea of stretch zone
由此引出"拉伸区"的概念
And I didn't realize how much stronger I would become
我以前没有意识到当我拉伸自己
when I stretch myself and do things that weren't in
去尝试做一些在我的拉伸区
things in my stretch zone and my panic zone
和恐慌区里的事时 我有多强大
I just thank you
谢谢你
because I think this class has really been the road map
我觉得这门课对我们很多人来说
A lot of us have needed to change and becomes happier
就像地图一样指引我们改变 变得快乐
So thank you
谢谢
Thank you
Good afternoon, everyone
各位下午好
I'd like to first of all say you are great. Yeah
我首先想说你太棒了
And also I am a proud educator in the Milwaukee public school system
我是Milwaukee公立学校体系的一名老师
Are there any future educators in the room?
在座有将来想做老师的吗
＂Milwaukee!＂
"Milwaukee"
And what you speak of
你之前讲过的
as Albert Bandura and the theory of self efficacy
Albert Bandura和自我效能理论
is so very important
是非常重要的
And anyone who is interested in youth empowerment or education
任何对帮助青年成长或教育有兴趣的人
it's very, very important
对孩子们有高期望
No.1 to have high expectations for our children
是非常非常重要的
especially children of color
尤其是有色人种的孩子
cause as an educator
作为教育工作者
I see what Bandura talks about and what Dweck talks about
我明白Bandura和Dweck想表达的意思
this diminished sense of reality for these kids
对这些孩子来说弱化了的现实
that produces whole other world for them
为他们创建了一个完全不同的世界
So you know I just want to really focus and kind of stress that
我想强调并着重突出这一点
And thank you for sharing that
很感谢你讲了这个
That's important to have high expectations for children
对孩子有高期望是很重要的
and for yourselves of course
当然对自己也是很重要的
Right. Beliefs in self-fulfilling prophecies so often create the world
没错 自我实现预言经常会改变世界
our world and the world of those around us
我们的以及我们周围的世界
based on our beliefs
基于我们的信仰
Let's take a couple of more
我们再听几位
And I'll do my quick summary
然后我再快速总结一下
Yes
请说
OK
好的
Go for it
请讲吧
I know this has been mentioned a couple times already
我知道这已经被提到好几次了
but it's so easy to blame others for our unhappiness
但真的很容易将我们的不快乐归咎他人
or others' actions
或他人的行为
or even our own actions for our unhappiness
甚至我们自己的行为
But you've talked so many times about what's going on
但你说过很多次我们潜意识中
in our own subconscious and how
发生的事以及
what subconscious may be doing
潜意识的影响
is might actually preventing our unhappiness
可能才是阻止我们不快乐 错了
preventing our happiness rather
阻止我们快乐的原因
And it just brought me back to Marva Collins
这让我回想起Marva Collins
and how if a student did something wrong
如果学生做错了什么事
she made them go through the alphabet and say
她会让他们看一遍字母表说
these are all good things about me
这些都是我好的方面
And it's really been enlightening to try to think about
我们真的应该尝试去想
how am I thinking what am I not doing to others
我想的是什么 对他人不做什么
or what others are doing to me
或他人对我做什么
but what am I thinking that's preventing me from being a happier person
但要思考是什么阻止我变成一个更幸福的人
That's wonderful. Thank you
很好 谢谢
Let's take two more
再听两位同学
So up there
那位同学
I guess two things that really stuck with me from the class is
这门课上我印象最深的两样东西就是
the little clip you showed of the baby learning to walk
你放的小宝宝学走路的录像
And just like what you conveyed the idea like this baby
你想表达的是这个宝宝
has no reason to like have a sense of why he's falling down
并不知道他为何会摔倒
and it should be anything that he should be ashamed of
也不知道他该为此感到羞耻
And that was just like a very effective way to kind of convey like
这是种很有效的方法让我们知道
we always saying kind of learn to fail and fail to learn
我们要学会失败 从失败中学习
That really stuck with me
这让我感触良多
And also your own willingness to describe your own kind of rises
以及你愿意说出你自己在做
and falls as you went through your studies of psychology
心理学研究时经历的起起伏伏
and your experiences at Cambridge and Harvard
以及你在剑桥和哈佛的经历
and just your willingness to be very open about it
你愿意很开诚布公地和我们分享
It's kind of empowering like, for me is
这让我感受到
I'm about to graduate and I go forward
我要毕业了 要继续发展
kind of maybe don't know what exactly you want to do
并不清楚自己想做什么
and you consider different options
会考虑各种选择
and obviously that fear of failures
会感受到对失败的恐惧
especially when you come from a place like Harvard
尤其是来自像哈佛这样的地方
is maybe especially xx
更是让人倍感压力
You just you are willing to share these experiences and empowering
而你愿意和我们分享这些经历
I feel as I kind of question the choices I am going to make
我就会重新考虑我要做的决定
So I really appreciate that
对此我非常感谢
Thank you
谢谢
Yes
请说
Every day is a beautiful day
每一天都是美好的
And to be grateful for that somehow makes it easier to go out
对此感恩能够让我们在做自己
and try to do things that maybe even we didn't like
不喜欢的事时能更轻松
And common sense is not that common
以及常识其实并不那么人尽皆知
And these are all - a lot of things that I've learned I already knew
这些都是... 学的很多东西都是我已经知道的
but now I learned it at Harvard
但我现在是在哈佛学到的
Great. All right
好的 很好
Let's take one more
我们再听一位同学
So I'm senior and I'm leaving
我是大四的 马上要毕业了
So this is my last lecture class at Harvard
这可能是我在哈佛上的最后一节课
So I apologize if this message seems a little more geared
如果我说的东西对于班里的低年级同学
towards the undergrads in the class
太过难以接受 我将为此道歉
one of the things that I'm very impressed with
我印象非常深刻的一点是
is a large lecture class that is so far reaching
这样一门涉及面广泛的大课
as far as the number of people who want to take it
有如此多人想上这门课
and the diversity of students in the class
班里的同学各种各样
But I guess this experience that I like to share is that
但我想和大家分享的经历就是
I came into this class
我来到这个课堂
admittedly because I value honesty I will say I took it
我很诚实 必须承认
because I thought it would be a nice complement
我认为这会是对艰难的大四
to an otherwise a difficult senior spring
春季学期一个很好的补充
And I thought,＂Well, it'll be nice class to have.＂
我就想"这应该是门挺好玩的课"
And my sophomore year
在我大二时
I had gone through kind of a self discovery
我有点开始探索自我
post depression that made me kind of value things in a different way
压抑的生活让我用不同的方式来看待事物
So I've been
我当时
I've been using these lessons that I learned sophomore year
我有了大二的这些想法
And I thought＂Well maybe this class will just be redundant＂
我就想"也许这门课就是多余的了"
Turns out I went through another really difficult time
结果后来我又在大四的春季学期
during my senior spring
经历了艰难的时期
And um... Sorry
抱歉
I guess what I'd like to relate to especially the undergrads here
我最想和在座的低年级同学分享的
is that it's very important if you are a freshmen
就是如果你是大一的
if you are a sophomore
大二的
it's not even too late as juniors
甚至大三都不算晚
it's very important to prioritize
最重要的是搞清楚
what's really important to you at this school
在学校里对你最重要的是什么
And let me tell you it's not the paper
我告诉你们不是论文
it's not the problem set
不是讨论的问题
it's not getting a full 8 hours sleep
不是当你的朋友需要你
when your friends need your attention for an hour
空出一小时时 你却说要保证八小时睡眠
because the people here matter the most
因为这里的人是最重要的
And you'll miss them
你以后会想念他们
And if you don't spend time with them now
如果你不珍惜现在和他们一起的时光
you won't have time to spend time with them later on
以后很难再有时间和他们共度
So it's very important
这非常重要
prioritize what is meaningful for you
搞清楚真正对你有意义的是什么
and what you really, really want to do in this school
和你在学校中真正想做的事
because before you know it
因为在你不经意间
it will be over
它就要结束了
So thank you for helping me remember that
谢谢你让我铭记这一点
and making it meaningful semester
使我的这个学期变得有意义
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you
谢谢 谢谢你们
Let me summarize
现在我来总结一下
All of these things that you already mentioned before
你们刚刚讲到的这些所有东西
these are not necessarily the most important
这些不一定是最重要的
These are the ones that
这些东西
for me without looking back on my notes came up
我无须翻阅笔记就能想到
First
首先
the questions that you ask
你所问的问题
will very often determine the quest that you take
经常都会决定你所做的探索
And if we only ask the negative questions such as
如果我们只问消极的问题 比如
＂why do so many of these individuals fail?＂
"为什么这么多人失败"
Then we won't see the potential for greatness
我们就没法看到潜藏在
that exists in each individual if we only ask
每个人心中的伟大 如果我们只问
＂How can my relationship be improved?＂
"我的人际关系该怎样改善"
Then we will not see all the wonders and the treasures
我们就无法看见身边的人
and the miracle that exist in the person next to us
所拥有的宝贵财富和奇迹
We also need to ask the positive question
我们同样要问积极的问题
what is good about my relationship?
我的人际关系中有什么好的方面
What is great about my partner?
我的同伴有哪些优点
What is wonderful about myself?
我自己有哪些优点
What is meaningful to me?
什么对我最有意义
What is pleasurable to me?
什么能使我愉快
What am I good at?
我擅长什么
Questions start a quest
问题会带来探索
And the kind of the quest they start depends on the quality
探索的内容取决于我们
of the question that we ask
所问的问题
The four minute mile - beliefs create reality
我们常说信念创造现实
Not only beliefs, but to a great extent
不仅是信念 更宽泛地说
how we perceive reality is what actually comes true
我们如何理解现实才是最后所得的结果
Marva Collins believed in her students
Marva Collins相信她的学生
believes in her students and miracles happen
相信她的学生 然后奇迹发生了
Those unteachable ones become extraordinary because of beliefs
那些朽木难雕的学生因为信念而成就卓越
Remember John Carlton's study once again about business school graduates
还记得John Carlton关于商学院学生的研究吗
Two thing distinguish the extraordinary from the rest
将卓越和平庸划分开的有两样东西
One was that they were always asking question
一个是他们总在问问题
always wanting to learn more
总想学习到更多
having that humbleness that's so important for growth and well being
心怀谦逊 对成长 幸福和自尊
and self esteem
尤为重要
And second
其次
they believed in themselves
他们相信自我
They had the confidence
他们有自信
They had the self efficacy to succeed and to thrive
他们有自我效能通往成功和进步
How do we improve the belief?
我们如何提升信念?
By putting ourselves on the line, by coping
通过拉伸自我 去尝试
by taking risks
挑战自我
by showing ourselves that we can do it through visualization
通过具象化使我们明白自己可以做到
There are no short cuts to success
成功没有捷径
Learn to fail or fail to learn
学会失败 从失败中学习
It is no coincident that the most successful
历史上很多成功的杰出人士
extraordinary people in history were also the ones
同样也是那些失败最惨重的人
who failed the most
这并非巧合
whether it was in sports, Babe Ruth
无论是在体育界 Babe Ruth
who struck out more than any other players of his time
比同时代任何球员三振出局次数都多
but also hit the most home runs
但也打出过最多的全垒打
whether it was Michael Jordan
还有Michael Jordan
who described his failures time and time again
一次次地表现出失败
whether it's taking the game winning shot where he didn't make it
赛点时最后一个绝杀没有投进
or practicing over and over and over again
或不断重复的机械训练
It's no coincident that Thomas Edison
Thomas Edison 比任何科学家
the person who had more patents
获得专利都多的人
than any other scientist in history
同样也是失败过最多次的人
is also the scientist who had failed the most times
这也并非巧合
Remember Dean Simonton's work on scientists as well as the artists
还记得Dean Simonton对科学家和艺术家的研究吗
The most successful ones were also the ones who failed the most
最成功的往往是失败得最多的
There is no other way to learn
没有别的方法可以学习
Moreover if we accept this
而且如果我们接受这一点
if we accept this growth mindset
如果我们接受这种成长的心态
as opposed to fixed mindset that Carol Dweck talks about it
而不是Carol Dweck所说的固定心态
Not only we will be, improve more
我们不仅会更有进步
we will also be happier
也会更加快乐幸福
because then not every experience is a threat to our ego
因为这样就不会每次经历都是
to our self, to our self esteem
对自我 自尊的一种威胁
If we accept the failure is inevitable
如果我们接受失败是不可避免的
whether in a relationship
不管是在人际关系中
there are disappointments and arguments
存在失望和争吵
or in individual life
还是在个人生活
or on a national level
或从国家来说
no perfect country, no perfect person
没有完美的国家 没有完美的人
no perfect organization
没有完美的组织
And if we understand that life is about this
如果我们明白生命是个上升的螺旋
as opposed to about this
而非一条直线
we'll be so much happier
我们会幸福得多
so much calmer
冷静得多
and paradoxically so much more successful
并且也更加成功
The permission to be human - there are two kinds of people
允许为人 世界上有两种人
who don't experience painful emotions
不会经历情感创伤
Who are they again?
哪两种人
The psychopath and dead people
精神病患者和死人
I'm so glad none of you are psychopath and that you are all alive
我很高兴你们都不是精神病患者 也都活着
It makes the class so much better
这让这门课好上很多
so much safer
安全很多
You are not going to come out of this class
你不可能学完这门课后
experience a constant high
就能一直保持人生平顺
No one experiences a constant high
没人能一直保持人生平顺
You are going to continue to have those ups and downs
你还会经历坎坷起伏
The only difference I hope
我希望你们唯一能
that you will experience now is that when you experience a painful emotion
感受到的区别就是当经历感情创伤时
you will look at it and say
你会看着它说
＂Oh, I'm human. It hurts
"我只是普通人 我很难过
I wish it weren't that way
真希望事情不是这样
but I accept it
但我接受它
just like you accept the law of gravity
就像接受重力定律一样
because the law of gravity is as much part of physical nature
因为重力定律是一种物理本质
as painful emotion is a part of human nature
就像感情创伤是一种人性本质
Permission to be human
允许为人
We talked about many interventions that work in this class
在课堂上我们讲了很多种干预
Most interventions don't work as we've seen
大多数干预并不起作用 正如
whether it's with the Somerville study or others
Somerville的研究和其他研究显示的
Journaling works
而日记可以
When we write, when we open up
在写东西时 我们在打开内心
whether it's in writing or sharing with a person we care about
不管是写 还是和我们关心的人倾诉
And it can be a therapist
可以是心理咨询师
It can be our best friend, our partner
可以是好朋友 爱人
When we share, when we open up
当我们分享 开放内心时
we are able to make sense
我们就能建立一种感觉
create ＂a sense of coherence＂ in the words of Antonovsky
用Antonovsky的话来说就是"关联性的感觉"
about the experiences of our lives
来看待我们生命中的经历
and enjoy higher levels of happiness
得到更高层次的快乐
It works
这是有用的
There are so many treasures of happiness all around us and within us
我们周围和内心有那么多快乐
And the question is do we notice them?
而问题在于我们注意到它们了吗
Or do we take them for granted?
还是把它们想成理所当然
Remember the word, appreciate
回忆一下appreciate这个词
It has two meanings:
有两种意思
one is to say thank you for something which is a nice thing to do
一种是表示谢谢 这是很好的
again, sister called the gratitude is the highest of virtues
人们常说感恩是最高尚的美德
It's a nice thing to be grateful
感激是一件很好的事
The second meaning is no less important
第二种意思也同样重要
Appreciate means to grow
意思是增值
And when we appreciate the good in our lives
当我们感激生活中好的方面
when we appreciate the good in our relationship
感激人际关系中好的方面
when we appreciate our partner
感激我们的伴侣
our friends, our classmates
朋友 同学
when we appreciate our country
感激我们的国家
the good grows
这些好处就会增值
Unfortunately the opposite is also the case
不幸的是相反的事也会发生
When we don't appreciate
但我们不予以感恩时
the good depreciates
好的方面就会贬值
There is no perfect relationship
世上没有完美的人际关系
no perfect person, no perfect country
没有完美的人 没有完美的国家
The important thing though is to focus on what is working
最重要的是要关注什么是有效的
Appreciate it so that it appreciates
感激它 它才能增值
So many people wonder why they are not happy
很多人疑惑自己为什么总是不快乐
even though they have all the things that they want in their lives
即使他们已经得到了想得到的一切
Why? Because there can be too much of a good thing
为什么 因为好东西太多有时也不是好事
Remember my favorite piece of music?
还记得我最喜欢的歌吗
Whitney Houston - And I Will Always Love You
Whitney Houston的《我将永远爱你》
Straight 10
10分满分
Second favorite: Beethoven's 9th, 9.5
第二喜欢的 贝多芬第九交响乐 9.5分
Play together - play together: noise
在一起播放 就是噪音
Not 19.5, not 10, not 5
不是19.5分 10分或5分
Noise
只是噪音
There can be too much of a good thing
好东西太多也不是好事
Easier said than done to simplify
要将一切简化说起来容易 做起来难
But remember that a much better predictor
但记住我们说过比物质充裕
of well being than material affluence is time affluence
更能带来幸福的是时间充裕
Simplify. Assert yourself
简化 果断坚决
Say no at times when it's appropriate
在适当的时候学会说"不"
Find out what you really, really
弄清楚你究竟
really want to do with your life and do it
真正想做的东西 然后去做
The No.1 predictor of well being - relationships
最能预示幸福的是 人际关系
The No.1 predictor of well being
是最能预示幸福的
an intimate relationship that you cultivate now and in the future
你现在和未来所经营的一段
matters more than anything else in the world
亲密关系比世界任何事都重要
Yes, even more than a problem set
对甚至比问问题更重要
even more than an exam
比考试更重要
even more than how wildly successful we are
比我们有多成功 多被人景仰
and how admired we are
更重要得多
Yeah, that will lead to a spike in our well being
对 成功会使我们的幸福感陡升
very quickly will go back to base level
而很快又降到基础水平
just like the tenure professors went back to the base level
就像获得长期聘用的大学教授
Just like the lottery winners
就像彩票中了大奖的人
And the highly successful individuals
那些以为自己
who thought they had made it
非常成功的人
and went to the base level and below
很快会回到基准水平甚至更低
because they didn't know what would make them happier
因为他们不知道什么会让他们更快乐
Well, this is what can
这就是一种
one of the things that can make us happier
其中一种让我们更快乐的方法
And to cultivate relationship means to invest in them
经营一段感情就意味着为之投入
to put time into them
向其中投入时间
To share, to open up
彼此分享和交流
Just like we would invest
就像我们会投入
if we found our ideal job, ideal workplace
如果我们找到理想的工作
we would start to invest then
我们会将自己投入其中
Same with relationship
人际关系也是一样
Remember movies end where love begins
电影总是在结尾时爱情才开始
It's about cultivating the relationship after the screen comes down
在大屏幕暗下来后继续经营感情
after the sunset - that's where the investment
在日落之后 此时我们的投入
that's where the return of investment comes
我们的投入才有了回报
Our mind can only take us only so far
思想带给我们的前进是有限的
You know I know positive psychology pretty well
我很了解积极心理学
I apply everything that I talk about here
我实践了所有我教的知识
However, I really think that if I was not
然而我真的觉得如果
cognizant of the body mind connection
我不知道精神肉体联系
and applying the body mind connection to my life
并将精神肉体联系应用于我的生活
I would be far less happy than I am today
我一定没有今天这么快乐
Why? Because I would be compromising on my base level God's given
为什么 因为我会屈服于上帝决定的基准水平
gene's given level of well being
基因决定的基准幸福水平
Because when we don't  exercise
因为当我们不锻炼时
it's like taking a depressant
就像打了镇静剂
And we have to fight our nature
我们必须和本性抗争
And it's very hard to fight our nature
和本性抗争是很难的
It's very difficult to enhance our levels of well being
提升我们幸福的水平是很难的
as is to have to also fight against nature is incredibly difficult
而同时要和本性抗争则是难以想象的困难
So remember the wonder drug
还记得灵药吗
Exercise at least four times a week for 30 minutes
每周锻炼四次 每次半小时
If you can, if you are interested
如果可以 如果你有兴趣
do some formal yoga or mindful meditation
去做做瑜伽或冥想
sitting meditation
打坐冥想
If not, at the very least
如果不行 那么至少
breathe -breathe deeply a few times a day
每天深呼吸几次
Three deep breaths can make a big difference
三次深呼吸就有显著效果
Now is not a bad time to do it
现在就可以试试
Sleep - when possible 8 hours or somewhere around 8 hours a night of sleep
睡眠 可能的话八小时或接近八小时
And touch
以及触摸
Hug, embrace - an underused sense is so important
抱 拥抱 这个总被忽视的感官却非常重要
Be known rather than be validated
被了解而非被证明
And again, all of us have the need to be validated
我们所有人都需要被证明
It's not about getting rid of our dependent self esteem
并不是说要完全去除我们依赖别人的自尊
but it is very much about first and foremost being known expressing
但更首要的是被了解 去表达
rather than impressing
而非给他人留下印象
Life becomes so much lighter, so much easier
人生会变得更轻松 更简单
so much more exciting
更让人兴奋
when we are about expressing ourselves
如果我们能表达自我
Being known rather than being validated
被了解而非被证明
whether it's with our romantic partner
无论是和我们的伴侣
our family, our friends, our colleagues, our class
家人 朋友 同事 同学
the foundation of the growth of intimacy
这都是在长期人际关系中
and passion in long term relationships
亲密和激情增加的基础
Easier said than done
说起来容易做起来难
It's so important
这非常重要
Now I tried to have top 10
我想列出前十
but I couldn't. I had to have one more
但我做不到 有一个不得不提
so you'll have to excuse me
所以你们要谅解
The last one and the one that brings together all the others
最后一点 能将所有东西整合在一起的一点
on so many levels is the one about change
就是关于转变的内容
Finally. You've been waiting the entire semester just for this - well
终于讲到了 你们一整个学期就等着它呢
was worth the wait I hope
希望不会辜负你们的期待
There are two types - I mean there are many types
有两种... 事实上有很多种类型
but there are also two types of graduates
但有两种类型的学生
from 1504 or any other class or workshop
上过这门课或其他
that is about attaining higher levels of happiness
关于获得更高层次的幸福的课
One that at best enjoys a temperate high
一种是会感觉很愉快
Or nice memory and goes back down to base level
或美好的回忆 然后回到基准水平
And the second that enjoys maybe the same temperate high
第二种同样感觉很愉快
which cannot last our entire lives
虽然不可能持续整个人生
but still enjoy continuous growth throughout their lives
但仍然在未来持续增长
And the difference, the primary difference
其区别 最基本的区别就在于
is whether or not you introduce behavioral changes
你是否发生了行为转变
Remember Peter Drucker - what he said
还记得Peter Drucker说过
whenever people came to him for a weekend - seminar intensive
每当人们去参加他的周末研讨班
he said on Monday
他周一时都会说
＂Don't call me to tell me how wonderful it was
"别打电话跟我说这课有多棒
Call me and tell me what you are doing differently.＂
而是告诉我你开始变得不一样了"
Because in his 65 years of experience working with the most successful
在他和世界上最成功 最出色
the most inspiring
最聪明的人
the best and the brightest people in the world
一起合作的六十五年间
what he's found that this is what extinguishes real
他发现这才是能让人
lasting change from a temperate high
一直保持愉悦平和的原因
Don't tell me how wonderful it was
不要告诉我这课有多棒
Tell me what you are doing differently on Monday
告诉我你周一做了什么改变
Introduce behavioral changes now
从现在开始进行行为转变
This is the core of change
这就是改变的核心
What you learned in this class hopefully is only the beginning
你们在这门课上学到的只是开始
only the beginning
仅仅是开始
because remember once again Carlton's study
回忆下在Carlton的研究中
The people who succeed, the most who are the happiest
成功的人 最快乐的人
succeed the most in the ultimate currency
就最成功地实现了终极目标
in a long term ones who are lifelong learners
从长远来看 他一生都在学习
always asking questions, always finding out more
永远在问问题 永远探索
But there are many people with good intentions
有很多人都有很好的意图
many people with good intentions
很多人都有很好的意图
but good intentions are not enough
但很好的意图还不够
What we also need is the foundation
我们需要的还有基础
the empirical, rigorous
实用的 严格的
scientific foundation of things that work
科学的基础来起作用
And when we know these things
当我们了解这些东西后
then we pay them forward
再将它们传递出去
then we share them
和他人分享
In psychology among other social sciences and sciences in humanities
在很多人文及社会的学科中 包括心理学
"What you got here at Harvard? What are you getting here at Harvard?"
"你在哈佛收获了什么 得到了什么"
is that foundation that can
就是这样一种基础
that can make the world a better place
来使世界变得更美好
I don't teach this class only because it is fun for me
我教这门课不仅因为觉得它有趣
it is fun; yes, it is very pleasurable to me
它确实很有趣 我觉得很愉快
I told you I can't wait for Tuesdays and Thursdays
我说过我总是等不及到周二和周四
to share what I care about the most with you
来和你们分享我最关心的东西
Yes it's fun
是很有趣
But I don't do it just because of that
但我教这门课不仅仅因为这个
I do it because I think the ideas of  some of the greatest psychologists
更因为我认为一些伟大心理学家的想法
that I have quoted and cited and discussed
我引用过 也讨论过的
their ideas can change the world for the better
他们的想法能使世界变得更好
Maslow back in 1954 wrote:
1954年时Maslow写道
＂I am not only the disinterested and impersonal seeker
"我不仅是对纯粹的冷漠真理
for pure cold truth for its own sake
公正客观的探索者
I am also very definitely interested and concerned with man's fate
我也很有兴趣关注人类的命运
with his ends and goals and with his future
其结局 目标以及未来
I would like to help improve him and better his prospects
我想帮助人类进步 改善其前景
I hope to help teach him how to be brotherly
我希望教会他如何友爱他人
cooperative, peaceful, courageous
和平互助 勇敢坚毅 正直公平
and just, I think science is the best hope for achieving this
我认为科学是达到这个目标最大的希望
and of all the sciences
而在所有学科中
I consider psychology most important to this end
我认为心理学是最有潜力的
Indeed, I sometimes think
事实上我有时觉得
that the world will either be saved by psychologists
世界要么被广义的
in the very broadest sense
心理学家拯救
or else it will not be saved at all.＂
要么就无法被拯救"
In the broadest sense of psychologists
广义的心理学家
It doesn't mean that
这并不意味着
you now have to go on and get a PHD in psychology
你现在就应该去读个心理学的博士
or to concentrate in psychology
或潜心研究心理学
But it means to be constant cognizant
而是要时刻意识到
to be self aware of what is going on in here
了解你大脑中发生的一切
the most wondrous and amazing entity in the universe
这宇宙中最令人惊异的实体
to understand what's going on here
了解它发生的一切
and there, and here
周围环境以及你的心
and how they are connected
它们是如何联系在一起的
and to share it by being practical idealists
并作为现实理想主义者来分享它
And you can make a difference
你们可以有影响
You can make a difference
Because the one has incredible power
每个人都有不可思议的力量
Remember if you make three people smile
还记得吗 如果你让三个人微笑
and they make three other people smile
他们会让另外三个人微笑
After 20 interations you'll touch every single human being on the planet
如此20次后 就能传到地球上每一个人
Happiness is contagious
快乐是会传染的
Let me show you one last video of how happiness and joy is contagious
我再展示最后一段关于幸福快乐如何传染的录像
Dad is going to make you laugh now. Ready?
爸爸要惹你们笑了 准备好了吗
What kind of world that they will grow into depends on you
他们会在怎样的世界中成长取决于你
And it depends on whether or not you first and foremost
取决于你是否首先
take care of yourself
关注了自身
In the words of Gandhi
引用甘地的话
＂Be the change you want to see in the world＂
"欲变世界 先变其身"
If you want a happier world, be that change
如果想要更快乐的世界 你自己先快乐起来
All the places you will go
所有你们去的地方
I would like to remind you
我想提醒你们
that every time you go to a place and very often
每次你们去一个地方 通常情况下
you will fly to a place that every time you go
你都会坐飞机去 这样你每次去时
you will hear something that hopefully will trigger
都会听到一些会引起你反思
hopefully will remind you how important it is to take care of yourself
照顾自己有多重要的东西
because to take care of others
要照顾别人
you first and foremost need to take care of yourself
你首先要照顾自己
You know when you fly
当你坐飞机时
and the flight attendant says
乘务员会说
in case of any emergency and the oxygen mask comes down
以防紧急情况 氧气面罩会脱落
first help yourself before you help others who need your help
首先自己戴上 在去帮助需要帮忙的人
Because that is the source
因为这就是
the foundation of the golden rule
黄金法则的基础
It is the foundation of a better world
是更美好的世界的基础
The ultimate currency
终极目标
So each time you go to one of those wonderful places
每次你去某个美丽的地方
exotic or otherwise
国外或国内
remember to simplify
记住要简化问题
remember to take care of yourself
记住照顾自己
remember to exercise
记住要锻炼
remember to assert yourself and say no when appropriate
记住要果断坚决 在适当的时候说"不"
Remember to cultivate your relationships
记住要经营你的感情
Remember what it is that is really
记住你生命中什么才是
really important for you in your life
真正最最重要的东西
This experience
这个经历
this semester for me has been extraordinary
这个学期对我来说非常特别
And it was made extraordinary first by the amazing teaching staff
它之所以这么特别首先是因为这些
that we have
出色的教职员工
Won't you come up?
上台来吧
Just a few minutes. A few minutes. Not more. OK?
就几分钟 不用太长
You have no idea what kind of work was going on behind the scenes
你们不知道这幕后有多少工作
You have no idea how much
你们不知道
how much each and every one of the teaching staff
这每一个教职员工
the head TFs, Shawn and Debb and every one of the others
主管助教Shawn和Debb 以及其他助教
How much they put into cultivating that relationship with you
他们投入了多少时间来经营和你们的关系
how many hours they spent
他们花了多少小时
how much, how many mindful and heartful moments they spent
耗费了多少苦心和思考
So I would like to thank them, and I would like you to thank them
我想感谢他们 也希望你们能感激
for their presence
他们的存在和
for who they are
所做的工作
So thank you. Come up. Come up
谢谢你们 来吧 上来
there are many of those to be made
做这些很麻烦
But I'd like to give our TFs a little token of appreciation
但我想对我们的助教一些小小的表示
The way to celebrate your hard work?
来庆祝你们的辛勤付出
Do you want to say something?
你想说些什么吗
It's your turn
轮到你了
My turn.Thank you
轮到我了 谢谢
Quick, quick, quick. OK
快 快 快
So I actually just want to say thank you to all of our TFs
其实我只想说感谢所有的助教
for their great work
辛勤的付出
Thank you to all the students here, the extension students
感谢到场的所有同学 以及进修的同学
Most importantly
最重要的是
I'd like to thank my mo... No! I'd like to thank Tal
我想感谢我的妈...不 我要感谢Tal
So firstly I want to thank Tal's grandparents for surviving
首先我要感谢Tal的祖父母
for his parents for thriving
生下了他的父母
for you know what, yeah?
然后生下了... 是吧
for you know what
你们懂的
And I'd like to thank Tammy for putting a smile on Tal's face
我想感谢Tammy让Tal总是面带微笑
and Sherill and David for sharing him with us
以及Sherill和David将他和我们大家分享
And for the opportunity for all of us to be a little more human
感谢给了我们接触人性本质的机会
because we are humanless. So thank you
让我们更人性化 谢谢
We are not the only one who are in tons of grateful to you
要感激你的不仅仅只有我们
You've touched so many people here this semester and always
你这学期感动了在场这么多人 其实一直都是
But your students this semester all sent in thank you notes
但这学期你的学生都写了感谢信
and we've compiled them and bounded them for you
我们将它们集合成册送给你
For all the places you go to, take it with you
不管去哪你都可以将它带着
thank you
谢谢
That is volume 1 of the gratitude book
这是感恩书的第一部
More letters are coming in
以后还有更多的信
So you can still send them
你可以不断增加
And finally it wouldn't be...
最后的最后
We want a token for you to always remember this class
我们想给你一个表彰来记住这堂课
and this great opportunity
以及这次伟大的机会
something that you would hope to use
希望你以后每次上这门课时
every time you teach this class in the future
都会用到的东西
I mean no pressure
不要有压力
Because you are king leader, and this hat...
因为你是首席 所以这顶帽子
Thank you. Thank you
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you
太感谢了 谢谢
Just one more thing
还有一件事
One more, one more
最后一件事
Thank you. Thank you so much
谢谢 非常感谢
Just want to say two more things
还有两点要说的
I know we are over time
我知道已经拖堂了
I'm really sorr.. Well one minute
十分抱歉 再占用一点时间
I want to thank just a few other people
我还想感谢一些人
I would like to thank Barry Reid sitting at the back
我想感谢坐在后面的Barry Reid
And the wonderful crew
以及出色的摄制组
the wonderful crew who are bringing this class to your home
这些摄制人员将课堂带回你们家
to your computers
带到你们的电脑上
And finally
最后
I would like to thank you
我想感谢在座各位
Each and every one of you is an entire world
你们每一个人都是一整个世界
a world in the making
这个世界正在
in the making of this world - your world
正在使你我所处的这个世界
our world a better place
变得愈发美好
So thank you
谢谢
And take care
保重
Take a good care
Thank you
谢谢